ICE-CREAM
‏"مثلجات"
DELIVERY BY CHRISTMAS
‏مهمة توصيل قبل العيد المجيد
What's up, Maksiu? Everything's okay?
‏ما الأخبار يا "ماكشو"؟ أكلّ شيء بخير؟
I wanna pee.
‏أريد التبول.
Urgently? Okay, let's go.
‏بشكل عاجل؟ حسنًا، هيّا بنا.
Merry Christmas!
‏ميلادًا مجيدًا!
GRANDPA
‏"جدّي"
- Hello, Krzysiu. - I was at your place, Grandpa.
‏- مرحبًا يا "كشيشو". ‏- عرّجت عليك يا جدّي.
Congratulations. What did you want?
‏أحسنت. وماذا أردت؟
You know. Grandma promised me that ring.
‏كما تعلم، وعدتني جدتي بذلك الخاتم.
In that case, talk to her.
‏في هذه الحالة، تحدّث إليها.
I would, if she were alive.
‏لو كانت حية، لفعلت.
- Krzysztof, the investors. - One moment, okay?
‏- "كشيشتوف"، المستثمرون ينتظرون. ‏- هلّا تمهلني لحظة؟
Hello?
‏هل تسمعني؟
He...
‏هل…
Wetness all around. Reach out. Be happy.
‏الرطوبة في كلّ حدب وصوب. ‏الزعانف جانبًا رفع. نحو الفرح.
Can you manage by yourself?
‏هل يمكنك تدبّر الأمر وحدك؟
Just wait for me here, okay?
‏انتظرني هنا، اتفقنا؟
OUT OF ORDER CLOSEST WC - 13TH FLOOR
‏"خارج الخدمة. أقرب مرحاض في الطابق الـ13"
And you're here for what purpose?
‏وأنت ما الذي جاء بك إلى هنا؟
Then fire away.
‏تفضّل.
- Hi. - I'm here.
‏- مرحبًا. ‏- أنا هنا.
- Yes. Uh, this is everything. - I see.
‏- نعم. هذا كلّ شيء. ‏- فهمت.
Just the code.
‏أدخلي الرمز من فضلك.
- Maks? - No.
‏- "ماكس"؟ ‏- لا.
- Maksiu?
‏- "ماكشو"؟
- Looking for me? - No, no!
‏- هل تبحثين عنّي؟ ‏- لا.
Thank you! Uh, Merry Christmas!
‏شكرًا. ميلادًا مجيدًا!
I'll drop by, and this time don't pretend you're not there.
‏سآتي، وهذه المرة لا تتظاهر ‏بأنك لست في البيت.
I heard scuffling.
‏سمعتُ وقع خطوات.
Stop calling me, you're blocking the line.
‏كُف عن مهاتفتي فأنت تشغل الخط.
If I were dying, I wouldn't be able to call an ambulance.
‏لن أتمكن من طلب الإسعاف عند احتضاري.
If you start dying, Grandpa, just leave the ring in a visible place.
‏إذا كنت تحتضر يا جدّي، ‏فاترك الخاتم في مكان ظاهر.
Okay, come over, maybe I'll leave it.
‏حسنًا، تعال، ربما سأتركه.
Weren't you supposed to wait for your mom?
‏ألا يُفترض أن تنتظر أمك؟
Maks!
‏"ماكس"!
Maksiu?
‏"ماكشو"؟
You should mind your kid, not leave him alone to deal with a urinal.
‏عليك الاعتناء بطفلك، ‏وعدم تركه يستخدم المبولة بمفرده.
Um, well, thank you for taking care of Maks. Let's go.
‏حسنًا، أشكرك على الاعتناء بـ"ماكس". فلنذهب.
He said the "F" word. Can I say it?
‏لقد تفوه بكلمة بذيئة. هل أستطيع قولها؟
No, no, no. Better not.
‏لا، لا يجدر بك ذلك.
Merry Christmas, yeah?
‏ميلادًا مجيدًا!
Come on. Let's go.
‏هيّا، فلنذهب.
Oh no.
‏لا.
- Um... what's wrong? - Your son shredded my papers.
‏- ما الخطب؟ ‏- لقد أتلف ابنك أوراقي.
I won't leave here until night.
‏لن أغادر المكتب قبل المساء.
You know...
‏أتعلم…
I'm really sorry.
‏أنا آسفة جدًا.
Do you pick up things professionally?
‏هل أنت محترفة في الاستلام والتسليم؟
- Yes? - Hello. I have a pick-up. For Krzysztof.
‏- نعم؟ ‏- مرحبًا. جئت لأخذ طرد لـ"كشيشتوف".
A guy... in a suit.
‏هناك شابّ يلبس بدلة
Said you've got something for him.
‏قال إنّ لديك شيئًا له.
Give him my holiday regards.
‏انقلي له معايدتي.
He said it was something really important.
‏قال إنه شيء مهم جدًا.
If it's important, then why... didn't he come himself?
‏إن كان مهمًا، فلم لم يأت بنفسه؟
Some trouble at work. I don't know. I really don't want to interfere,
‏لديه مشاكل في العمل. ‏لا أعلم. لا أريد التدخل،
but he said it's a matter... of life and death.
‏لكنه قال إنها مسألة حياة أو موت.
Excuse me.
‏أرجو المعذرة.
I do actually have something for him.
‏في الواقع، لديّ شيء له.
Come in!
‏ادخلا.
Oh, that's Wilhelm. A member of the family.
‏هذا "فيلهم"، فرد من أفراد العائلة،
He spent more time with my wife than I did, so I immortalized him.
‏وعاش مع زوجتي أكثر ‏مما عشت معها، لذا خلّدتُه.
Mom, a frigate! A clipper! The fastest sailing ships!
‏أمي، هاتان فرقاطة وقلبر، ‏أسرع السفن الشراعية!
Yeah, I sailed around the whole world on that one.
‏أجل، أبحرت حول العالم على متن تلك السفينة.
- Can you help me wrap the gift up? - Sure.
‏- هلّا تساعدينني في تغليف الهدية؟ ‏- بكل سرور.
And... this is for Krzysztof, right?
‏هذه لـ"كشيشتوف"، صحيح؟
Yeah. He likes this kind of stuff.
‏نعم، إنه يحب هذه الأشياء.
- When will he get it? - Delivery by Christmas.
‏- متى سيستلمها؟ ‏- التسليم قبل عيد الميلاد.
Company policy.
‏هذه سياسة الشركة.
Maks!
‏"ماكس"!
Thank you. Goodbye!
‏شكرًا لك. وداعًا.
Ahoy!
‏مع السلامة.
- What's that? - Oh, a trifle. I'll deliver it on the way.
‏- ما هذا؟ ‏- طرد صغير سأوصله في طريقي.
Sweet of the Chimney. Thanks.
‏سكاكر المدخنة. شكرًا.
Kama... Maks' gift was supposed to arrive.
‏كان يُفترض أن تصل هدية "ماكس".
The guys were to redirect the package, but it's not here.
‏كان على العمال جلب الطرد، لكنه ليس هنا.
Not everyone's back yet. It'll be here.
‏لم يرجع الجميع بعد. سيجلبونه.
Hiya!
‏مرحبًا.
Hiya, kid!
‏مرحبًا يا فتى.
- One, two, three... One... - The speech.
‏- واحد، اثنان، ثلاثة… واحد… ‏- الخطاب.
Uh, welcome, all employees.
‏أهلًا بجميع الموظفين.
So, yes. Christmas Eve is, uh...
‏نعم. ليلة عيد الميلاد…
This is, um, could be the time to sum things up.
‏قد تكون الفرصة المناسبة لمراجعة الأمور.
I've been with you for a few weeks now.
‏أنا معكم منذ أسابيع،
Thank you very much... for bestowing your trust upon me.
‏وأشكركم شكرًا جزيلًا على منحي ثقتكم.
An... and trust, as we know, is a key... core...
‏وكما تعلمون الثقة هي المفتاح، ‏بل الثقل المرجح…
I work on my core every day.
‏أنا أرفع الأثقال يوميًا.
As statistics show...
‏كما تُظهر الإحصائيات،
Christmas Eve is the time of miracles!
‏ليلة عيد الميلاد هي وقت المعجزات.
And that's why I wanted to wish you all the best.
‏لذا أردت أن أتمنى لكم كلّ التوفيق.
I would also like to say, uh... that...
‏وأود أن أقول أيضًا…
Now, imagine a lion.
‏والآن تخيّل أسدًا.
- Yes, you are the lion. - Yes, I am.
‏- أجل، أنت الأسد. ‏- أجل، أنا كذلك.
You're a charismatic predator,
‏أنت المفترس ساحر الجماهير،
a determined mammal who always gets what he wants.
‏الثديي العنيد الذي ينال دومًا ما يريد.
Nobody knows how to use that PA system, so don't worry.
‏لا أحد يجيد استخدام مكبر الصوت، فلا تقلق.
Come to the party.
‏تعال إلى الحفل.
The director has no time to party.
‏المدير ليس لديه وقت للحفلات.
He leads the pride.
‏على المدير أن يقود القطيع.
The pride is, uh... is there right now.
‏القطيع في الحفل حاليًا.
The team doesn't like me.
‏فريق العمل لا يحبني.
Beginnings are always hard.
‏البدايات صعبة دومًا.
And... you don't have to be a lion the whole time.
‏وليس عليك أن تكون أسدًا طوال الوقت.
Besides... uh, I'm sure there's someone who likes you.
‏إلى جانب ذلك، أنا متأكدة من وجود شخص يحبّك،
Back there... or somewhere else.
‏في الحفل أو في مكان آخر.
Are you crazy?
‏هل جُننت؟
W-What, what was that?
‏لم فعلت ذلك؟
Well, you came to me.
‏أنت جئت إليّ.
Because... I felt sorry for you.
‏لأنني شعرت بالأسف عليك.
...who always gets what he wants.
‏…الذي ينال دومًا ما يريد.
Sometimes, a lion may be blinded by his success.
‏أحيانًا، يُعمي النجاح بصيرة الأسد،
But not you.
‏لكن هذا لن يحدث لك،
Because you have the heart of a lion.
‏لأن لديك قلب أسد.
We'll see... who's sorry tomorrow.
‏سنرى من سيشعر بالأسف غدًا.
- Hi, butterfly. - Beautiful night.
‏- مرحبًا يا فراشة. ‏- ليلة جميلة.
You're so hot too?
‏أتشعرين بالحر أيضًا؟
Can I drop off Maks at you tomorrow?
‏هل يمكنني ترك "ماكس" عندك غدًا؟
For two or three hours.
‏لساعتين أو ثلاث.
Grażka?
‏"غراجكا"؟
Wet hair?
‏شعرك مبلل؟
Without panties in the frost?
‏ومن دون سروال داخليّ في الصقيع؟
Cover up.
‏غطّي نفسك.
Help me.
‏ساعديني.
Marysiu, you're ok?
‏كيف حالك يا "ماريشا"؟
Very good. Better than ever.
‏بخير، بأفضل حال.
Finish this cigarette and come inside.
‏أطفئي هذه السيجارة وادخلي.
- Grażka. - Bye.
‏- "غراجكا". ‏- وداعًا.
Good night.
‏ليلة سعيدة.
24TH DECEMBER
‏"24 ديسمبر"
Uh, hello. I've got a package for Mirek.
‏مرحبًا، معي طرد للسيد "ميريك".
That's my son. I can take it.
‏إنه ابني، يمكنني استلامه.
Merry Christmas! All the best.
‏ميلادًا مجيدًا وأطيب الأمنيات!
Hello. Delivery.
‏مرحبًا. خدمة التوصيل.
A package for me?
‏طرد لي؟
- Yes. Goodbye. - Goodbye.
‏- نعم. وداعًا. ‏- وداعًا.
- Hello. - Oh, hello. Wonderful.
‏- مرحبًا. ‏- مرحبًا. رائع.
Thank you so much. Were there any problems?
‏شكرًا جزيلًا. هل واجهت أيّ مشكلة؟
None.
‏لا.
- Oh, hello. - Hello.
‏- مرحبًا.
Um, in that case, uh...
‏في هذه الحالة…
- No. There's no need. Merry Christmas! - No, really, 'cause... Please wait...
‏- لا، لا داعي. ميلادًا مجيدًا! ‏- بلى، لأن… انتظري رجاءً…
Oh, I don't have anything after all.
‏بعد كلّ هذا، ليس معي نقود.
No worries. Goodbye.
‏لا بأس. وداعًا.
- Hello? - Grandpa, what did you send me?
‏- نعم؟ ‏- ماذا أرسلت إليّ يا جدّي؟
You didn't get the ring? Wait, my cabbage stew is burning.
‏ألم تستلم الخاتم؟ ‏انتظر، يخنة الملفوف تحترق.
Auntie Gienia poured the flour.
‏سكبت العمة "جينيا" الطحين.
Maybe you could start decorating the Christmas tree, eh?
‏يمكنك البدء في تزيين شجرة عيد الميلاد.
'Cause Graża said that the dough was sticky
‏…لأن العمة "غراجا" قالت إن العجين لزج
and it's gonna stick.
‏وسيلتصق.
And the worst thing that can happen
‏وأسوأ ما يمكن أن يحدث للمرء
is when you stick to something you shouldn't. And you're stuck.
‏هو أن يلتصق بشيء لا يريده ويعلق به.
Maks, wash off that dough, okay?
‏اغسل يديك من العجين، اتفقنا؟
Mom, the gift!
‏أمي، الهدية!
Your gift!
‏هديتك!
- Have you written a letter to Santa? - I haven't.
‏- هل كتبت رسالة إلى "بابا نويل"؟ ‏- لا.
I'll write it for you. What would you like to get?
‏سأكتبها عنك. ما الهدية التي تريدينها؟
I've already got everything. I've got you. And a job.
‏لديّ كلّ شيء، لديّ أنت ولديّ وظيفة.
Mom, you should want something.
‏أمي، لا بد أنك تريدين شيئًا.
I want...
‏أريد…
Oh! The Christmas Eve map.
‏خريطة ليلة عيد الميلاد!
No, come on. What comes first?
‏لا، بحقك، ماذا علينا أن نفعل أولًا؟
- Well? - Decorating the tree?
‏- ما قولك؟ ‏- تزيين الشجرة؟
Exactly.
‏بالضبط.
Zbyszek. Move over.
‏"زبيشك"، ابتعد.
Zbyszek, Zbyszek...
‏"زبيشك"…
Mom!
‏أمي!
- Hello? - Maks, is that you?
‏- نعم؟ ‏- "ماكس"، أهذا أنت؟
We peed together yesterday, remember?
‏تبوّلنا معًا البارحة، أتذكر؟
Can you put your Mom on the phone?
‏هلّا تعطي الهاتف لأمك؟
She's busy now.
‏إنها مشغولة الآن.
Listen... And where's your Mom?
‏اسمع، أين أمك؟
- Here. - Which means where?
‏- في البيت. ‏- وأين العنوان بالتحديد؟
Merry Christmas to you.
‏ميلادًا مجيدًا!
- You're here for me? - Yes.
‏- هل جئت تقصدني؟ ‏- نعم.
It's the wrong package. Whatever's in here isn't for me.
‏استلمتُ الطرد الخطأ، وما فيه ليس لي.
We don't always get what we want.
‏ما كلّ ما يتمنى المرء يدركه.
You don't understand how serious this is.
‏أنت لا تفهمين مدى جدّية الموقف.
Oh... Excuse me, how did you even find me, huh?
‏المعذرة، كيف عرفت عنواني؟
You have a very intelligent child. I'm sorry, could you put on your uniform?
‏لديك ولد ذكي جدًا. ‏المعذرة، هلّا ترتدين ثياب العمل؟
There's work to do.
‏هناك مهمة يجب إنجازها.
You do know it's Christmas Eve? It's my day off.
‏ألا تعلم أنها ليلة عيد الميلاد؟ ‏إنه يوم إجازتي.
And... you won't do anything about this?
‏ألن تفعلي شيئًا حيال الأمر؟
It's Christmas!
‏اليوم عيد الميلاد!
Hi, Kama!
‏مرحبًا يا "كاما".
Hi, darling.
‏مرحبًا يا عزيزتي.
- This is a total mess. - Okay?
‏- إننا نواجه فوضى عارمة. ‏- وماذا بعد؟
Some client got the wrong package. Your deliveries from today are screwed up.
‏استلم بعض العملاء طرودًا خاطئة، ‏واختلط الحابل بالنابل في عملياتك اليوم.
But what do you mean?
‏ماذا تقصدين؟
The packages went to the wrong places. I don't know, something wrong with labels.
‏ذهبت الطرود إلى عناوين خاطئة. ‏لا أعلم، هناك خطأ في ملصقات العناوين.
Yours too, with the present for...
‏وطردك أيضًا الذي يحتوي هدية…
Kama, Kama, you're on a speaker right now, you know?
‏"كاما"، أسمعك من مكبر الصوت، أتفهمين؟
Your most important package.
‏أهمّ طرد لديك.
Oh, fuck!
‏تبًا!
- Mom, come on! - How did this happen?
‏- تعالي يا أمي. ‏- كيف حدث هذا؟
Christmas is a time of miracles.
‏عيد الميلاد وقت المعجزات!
So, where could Maks' present be?
‏وأين يمكن أن تكون هدية "ماكس"؟
At one of these addresses?
‏لدى أحد هذه العناوين؟
Good thing you only had four deliveries.
‏لحسن الحظ، كان لديك أربع عمليات توصيل فقط.
But take it easy, do it after Christmas.
‏لكن هوّني عليك، ‏وأجّلي الأمر إلى ما بعد عيد الميلاد.
I'll deal with it. Take care.
‏سأتدبر الأمر. اعتني بنفسك.
Marysia? What are you up to?
‏علام تنوين يا "ماريشا"؟
Next item on the list.
‏البند التالي.
Maksiu...
‏"ماكشو"…
CHRISTMAS EVE MAP MAKING GINGERBREAD
‏"صُنع كعك الزنجبيل"
- Finally. - Excuse me?
‏- أخيرًا. ‏- المعذرة؟
- Excuses accepted. We can go. - "We"?
‏- اعتذارك مقبول. يمكننا الذهاب. ‏- معًا؟
Please deliver this to the right person and retrieve my package.
‏سلّمي هذا للمستلم المعني واستردي طردي.
Why have you crossed me out?
‏لم شطبت اسمي؟
This is your address. This is my address.
‏هذا عنوانك، وهذا عنواني.
I've already got those two packages. I've got three addresses left.
‏معي طردان، وبقي لديّ ثلاثة عناوين.
But I need my package as soon as possible.
‏لكنني بحاجة إلى طردي في أقرب وقت ممكن.
I figured.
‏توقعت ذلك.
Someone tampered with it.
‏لقد تلاعب أحدهم بالعناوين.
Okay.
‏حسنًا.
I can manage on my own.
‏بوسعي تدبّر الأمر وحدي.
I doubt that.
‏أشك في ذلك.
- Please leave. - You can go, friend.
‏- انزل رجاءً. ‏- انطلقي يا صديقتي.
So, we're friends now?
‏صرنا صديقين الآن؟
Krzysztof.
‏أنا "كشيشتوف".
Shouldn't a courier's route be closer to home?
‏ألا ينبغي أن يكون مسارك قريبًا من بيتك؟
This isn't my route. I'm substituting.
‏هذا ليس مساري. أنا أنوب عن زميلتي.
Gas.
‏البنزين.
- Diesel. - But it's running out, yeah?
‏- مازوت. ‏- لكنه يكاد ينفد، صحيح؟
That? That's the indicator. It's broken.
‏أتقصد هذا؟ إنه مؤشر الوقود وهو معطل.
So, how do you know... how much fuel is left?
‏وكيف تعرفين كمية الوقود المتبقية؟
Uh, today is Friday... I got a refill on Wednesday...
‏اليوم هو الجمعة، ‏وقد تزودت بالوقود يوم الأربعاء…
No, uh, no. On Monday.
‏لا، بل يوم الاثنين.
- I think, we shouldn't run out. - We shouldn't run out?
‏- يُفترض ألّا ينفد. ‏- "يُفترض ألّا ينفد"؟
How can you be sure?
‏وكيف تضمنين ذلك؟
It's like soft-boiling eggs, yeah? You just know when to take them out.
‏الأمر يشبه إعداد البيض البرشت، ‏تعرف بالفطرة متى يجهز.
No.
‏لا.
That's not how you soft-boil eggs.
‏هذه ليست طريقة إعداد البيض البرشت.
Fine. I trust my intuition, okay?
‏حسنًا، أنا أثق في حدسي، واضح؟
Your intuition.
‏حدسك.
'Cause of your intuition, we'll be... stuck in a field
‏بسبب حدسك، ستتقطع بنا السبل في حقل
or I'll have to run with a bucket to get some gas.
‏أو سأُضطر إلى الجري ‏حاملًا دلوًا لإحضار البنزين.
- Diesel. - Country dogs will bark at us.
‏- المازوت. ‏- ستنبح الكلاب الريفية علينا.
- So? Are you afraid of dogs? - That's not the point!
‏- وإن يكن؟ هل تخاف من الكلاب؟ ‏- هذا ليس بيت القصيد.
One must have a plan.
‏يجب أن تكون لديك خطة.
One must be prepared, think things through.
‏يجب أن تكوني مستعدة ‏وتُفكري في عواقب الأمور.
I've got a plan. I'm prepared for anything.
‏لديّ خطة وأنا مستعدة لكل شيء.
I can see that.
‏هذا واضح.
Did you turn on some kind of seat heating or what?
‏هل فعّلت وظيفة تدفئة المقاعد أو ما شابه؟
Oh, uh, you're sitting on my dryer.
‏لا، لكنك تجلس على مجفف شعري.
This is your plan?
‏أهذه خطّتك؟
Y... you've got a bathroom in... in your car.
‏هل مركبتك مزودة بحمّام؟
That's how I spice up my life, y'know? So I don't become a bore.
‏هكذا أضفي الإثارة على حياتي، ‏حتى لا أصبح شخصًا مملًا.
I got the hint.
‏فهمت تلميحك.
Where are we going?
‏إلى أين أنت ذاهبة؟
A FEW HOURS EARLIER
‏"قبل بضع ساعات"
Michał! Could you get that?
‏"ميخاو"، هلّا تفتح الباب؟
- Uh, hello. I've got a package for Mirek. - That's my son. I can take it.
‏- مرحبًا، معي طرد للسيد "ميريك". ‏- إنه ابني، يمكنني استلامه.
Merry Christmas! All the best.
‏ميلادًا مجيدًا وأطيب الأمنيات!
From some Milena. Maybe it's a gift?
‏المرسلة تُدعى "ميلينا". أهي هدية يا تُرى؟
Definitely a gift.
‏بالتأكيد هدية.
I'll open it and put it under the tree!
‏سأفتحها وأضعها تحت الشجرة.
He's a grown boy...
‏صار شابًا راشدًا،
and you're inspecting his stuff?
‏وما زلت تفتشين أغراضه؟
Honey?
‏يا عزيزي؟
Am I seeing things?
‏أأنا أتوهم؟
No, your eyes are fine, Mario la.
‏لا، نظرك سليم يا "ماريولا".
There you go. A gas station.
‏انظري، محطة وقود.
But you'd rather risk it, huh?
‏لكنك تفضّلين المخاطرة، صحيح؟
I'll do it for you. Here you go.
‏سأفعل ذلك من أجلك. تفضّل.
GAS STATION
‏"محطة وقود"
Fill it up.
‏عبّئها.
- Fill what up? - You wanted to fuel up, so go ahead.
‏- ماذا أعبّئ؟ ‏- عبّئ المركبة بالوقود بما أن هذا طلبك.
- Merry Christmas! - Yeah, yeah.
‏- ميلادًا مجيدًا! ‏- أجل.
I can help.
‏سأساعدك.
No, hold it. I'll pull.
‏لا، أنت أمسكه وأنا سأسحب الخرطوم.
- The hose is too short. - We can manage.
‏- الخرطوم قصير جدًا. ‏- يمكننا تدبّر الأمر.
If you could pass it under the car,
‏لو تتكرم بتمريره تحت السيارة
- I'll grab it on the other side. - Under where?
‏- حتى أمسكه من الطرف الآخر. ‏- تحت ماذا؟
It's Christmas. It pays to be nice to people.
‏نحن في عيد الميلاد، وحُسن المعاملة له ثواب.
Can you move the car?
‏هل يمكنك تحريك السيارة؟
Move the car.
‏حركي السيارة.
- What a nuisance. - What?
‏- كم هو مزعج! ‏- ماذا؟
Who's a nuisance?
‏من المزعج؟
She can't park properly and I'm supposed to...
‏إنها لا تجيد صفّ سيارتها، لكن يُفترض بي
drag the hose under the car?
‏أن أجرّ الخرطوم تحت السيارة؟
Here. You fill it up.
‏تفضّل. أنت عبّئها بالوقود.
Do it yourself.
‏افعل ذلك بنفسك.
- Hello.
‏- مرحبًا.
Our uncle got a hold of this reindeer
‏جلب عمّي هذه الرنة
and it's for my nephew, Jaś. He's four.
‏لابن أخي "ياش"، ابن الأربعة أعوام.
How do we erase this?
‏كيف نمحو هذا التسجيل؟
Auntie Krysia is an old cow! Kiss my hairy ass!
‏"العمة (كريشيا) بقرة عجوز! ‏قبّلي مؤخرتي المشعرة!"
All right. Uh, no point in struggling with this.
‏حسنًا. لا داعي إلى تكبد العناء مع هذه.
- This one should be fine. - Thank you.
‏- ستفي هذه بالغرض. ‏- شكرًا لك.
- You're welcome. Merry Christmas! - Thanks.
‏- على الرحب. ميلادًا مجيدًا! ‏- شكرًا.
- Come again.
‏- عاودي زيارتنا.
- Goodbye.
‏- وداعًا.
Hi, Dad.
‏مرحبًا يا أبي.
What are you doing here?
‏ماذا تفعل هنا؟
We've been calling you, but you're not picking up.
‏لقد اتصلنا بك مرارًا، لكنك لم تردّ.
Well, I'm at work.
‏أنا في العمل.
Has anything happened or...?
‏هل طرأ طارئ أم…
No.
‏لا.
Who's Milena?
‏من هي "ميلينا"؟
A friend from work. Why?
‏زميلتي في العمل. لم تسأل؟
Well... You got a package...
‏وصلك طرد
From that...
‏من تلك…
that girl,
‏من تلك الفتاة،
Milena.
‏"ميلينا".
HI DADDY!
‏"مرحبًا يا أبي!"
- Dad, this is some kind of joke. - M-m-mirek...
‏- هذه دعابة يا أبي. ‏- "ميريك"…
This looks like a serious matter to me.
‏يبدو لي أن الموضوع جدّي.
But Dad, this is impossible.
‏هذا مستحيل يا أبي.
Take it. Take one, 'cause your sugar level will be dropping now.
‏تفضّل، تناول واحدة، ‏لأن مستوى السكر في دمك سيهبط الآن.
- Take it. - I, I, I'll ask.
‏- تناولها. ‏- سأستفسر.
- Wa... wait here, I'll ask. - But Mirek, there's nothing to ask about!
‏- انتظر هنا، سأستفسر. ‏- لكن لا شيء يستوجب الاستفسار يا "ميريك".
Oh, it's you.
‏هذا أنت.
- You're smoking? - Yeah.
‏- هل تدخنين؟ ‏- نعم.
Why are you so spooked?
‏لم أنت مذعور؟
- I got... - Fucking Christmas!
‏- استلمت… ‏- تبًا لعيد الميلاد!
I tried moving a unicorn on a shelf and some kid bit me.
‏كنت أحاول تحريك وحيد قرن ‏على الرف فإذا بطفل يعضّني.
I got that surprise gift from you.
‏استلمت هديتك المفاجئة.
- Ohhhhhh... - Can I have one?
‏هل لي بسيجارة؟
And? Did you like it?
‏وماذا بعد؟ هل أعجبتك؟
I was kind of at a loss for words.
‏يعجز لساني عن التعبير.
Was it that Halloween party?
‏أحدث ذلك في حفل الهالوين؟
What if the kid was rabid?
‏ماذا لو كان الطفل مصابًا بداء الكلب؟
I'm off in a moment, but maybe... you wanna talk about it?
‏سأذهب بعد قليل، ‏لكن هل تريد التحدث عن الأمر؟
Drop by my house.
‏تعالي إلى بيتي.
It's kind of necessary now.
‏ربما هذا ضروري الآن.
Fuck, I hate kids.
‏تبًا، كم أكره الأطفال!
You'll heal in no time!
‏ستشفى قريبًا.
THE COUNTER SHOULD SHOW ZERO
‏"يجب أن يشير العدّاد إلى الصفر"
- All right, I'll go pay. How much? - You wanted to fill it up...
‏- حسنًا، سأدفع. بكم عبأتها؟ ‏- أنت أردت ملأها…
Sixty liters.
‏ستين لترًا.
Diesel. You were supposed to fill it with diesel.
‏المازوت، كان عليك تزويدها بالمازوت.
- Merry Christmas! To you, miss. - Goodbye.
‏- ميلادًا مجيدًا لك يا آنستي. ‏- مع السلامة.
Not much of a reserve.
‏الوقود الاحتياطي قليل.
You'll have to start cleaning on your own.
‏عليك التنظيف بنفسك من الآن فصاعدًا.
Your pants are crumpled.
‏سروالك مجعد.
The Grandparents are waiting.
‏جدّاك ينتظران.
What a beautiful tree. Did you decorate it yourself, Mirek?
‏يا لها من شجرة جميلة! ‏هل زيّنتها بنفسك يا "ميريك"؟
With Mom, like every year, Grandma.
‏بل مع أمي، مثل كلّ عام يا جدتي.
So, my darlings? I think it's time... to exchange wishes.
‏يا أحبائي، أظن أن الوقت ‏قد حان لتبادل التهاني.
When will she be here?
‏متى ستأتي؟
Who?
‏من؟
Mirek's lady friend.
‏صديقة "ميريك".
What friend?
‏أيّ صديقة؟
From work, Grandma. She got the address, but I don't know if she comes.
‏زميلتي في العمل. ‏لديها العنوان، لكن لا أعرف إن كانت ستأتي.
Then tell us about her. Come on!
‏أخبرنا عنها. هيّا!
Well, we... don't know each other very well.
‏لا يعرف أحدنا الآخر جيّدًا.
- We've... only spoken a few times. - Yes?
‏- لم نتحادث سوى بضع مرات. ‏- حقًا؟
I don't really know how this even happened.
‏لا أعرف كيف حدث هذا أصلًا.
You've got a kid and you don't know how it happened?
‏ستُرزق بطفل ولا تعرف كيف حدث ذلك؟
He made a baby?!
‏سيُرزق بطفل؟
Mirek has a baby?
‏هل سيصير "ميريك" أبًا؟
- What will it be? - No, uh...
‏- متى؟ ‏- لا…
I mean, I don't remember everything.
‏أقصد أني لا أتذكر كلّ شيء.
Maybe I can still get out of this somehow.
‏ربما ما زال بوسعي إيجاد مخرج.
Excuse me?
‏المعذرة؟
What do you mean "get out of this"?
‏ماذا تقصد بـ"مخرج"؟
Excuse me.
‏المعذرة.
Well... Mirek, go.
‏تحرّك يا "ميريك".
But what am I to tell her?
‏وماذا أقول لها؟
Tell her...
‏قُل لها…
Well?
‏ماذا؟
What do you usually say?
‏ماذا يُقال عادةً؟
You just babbled like a loon.
‏تمتمت لي بكلام كالمجانين.
Jesus Christ...
‏يا للهول!
But from the heart.
‏لكنه نابع من القلب.
Tell her... it will be all right.
‏قُل لها إن كلّ شيء سيكون على ما يُرام.
That you'll always be at her side and that you'll think of everything.
‏وإنك ستظل دومًا إلى جانبها ‏وإنك ستفكر في كلّ شيء.
After all, you work in a toy store, so you'll bring the kid...
‏في النهاية، أنت تعمل في متجر ألعاب، ‏لذا ستُحضر للطفل
- stuffed toys. - Yeah.
‏- دمى محشوة. ‏- أجل.
And since you still live with us, we'll help out too.
‏وبما أنك ما زلت تعيش معنا، فسنساعدك.
Hello, sir. I'm very sorry, but I delivered a package here this morning.
‏مرحبًا يا سيدي. ‏أنا آسفة جدًا، سلّمت طردًا إليكم صباحًا،
But there was a problem at the sorting office
‏لكن حدث لغط في مركز الفرز،
and there was a mistake. This is your package.
‏ووقع خطأ. هذا طردك.
You do have that package from this morning, right?
‏لا بد أن الطرد المسلّم صباحًا معك، صحيح؟
- That one wasn't for me? - No, no. I apologize.
‏- ألم يكن ذلك الطرد لي؟ ‏- نعم، ليس لك. أنا آسفة.
Just a second, okay?
‏أمهليني لحظة، اتفقنا؟
Yes...
‏نعم.
Oh, great. Thank you very much.
‏رائع. شكرًا جزيلًا لك.
- No, thank you. Uh... - All the best. Goodbye.
‏- شكرًا لك. ‏- مع أطيب أمنياتي. وداعًا.
Merry Christmas.
‏ميلادًا مجيدًا!
Goodbye.
‏مع السلامة.
There is no baby.
‏لا يُوجد طفل.
So, where is it?
‏وأين ذهب؟
The courier made a mistake. You were worried for nothing.
‏ارتكبت ساعية البريد خطأ. ‏لقد قلقتما بلا داع.
There won't be a baby?
‏ألن يكون هناك طفل؟
Can you pass the herring?
‏هلّا تعطيني الرنجة؟
But... this isn't it.
‏لكن هذا ليس طردي.
Seat belt.
‏ضع حزام الأمان.
A FEW HOURS EARLIER
‏"قبل بضع ساعات"
Hello. Delivery.
‏مرحبًا. خدمة التوصيل.
A package for me?
‏طرد لي؟
- Goodbye! - Goodbye.
‏- وداعًا.
From Estera?
‏المرسلة "إستيرا"؟
The giraffe loves the juicy pulp
‏تحب الزرافة اللب الغض
of acacia and commiphora leaves.
‏لأوراق الأكاسيا والبلسان.
While looking for a source of food
‏وأثناء البحث عن مصدر غذاء،
the giraffe may cross many kilometers.
‏قد تقطع الزرافة عدة كيلومترات.
It often follows the smell of distant rain.
‏وغالبًا ما تتبع رائحة المطر البعيد.
Trees are its salvation, even if the female has to
‏الأشجار هي خلاصها، ولو اضطرت الأنثى
extend its neck to reach the leaves.
‏إلى مد عنقها لبلوغ الأوراق.
I knew the most beautiful giraffes were in Botswana.
‏كنت أعلم أن أجمل الزرافات ‏تعيش في "بوتسوانا".
One would think that when a giraffe raises its head
‏قد يظن المرء أنه حين ترفع الزرافة رأسها،
the blood quickly drains from the brain
‏تنقطع الدماء بسرعة عن دماغها،
causing a loss of consciousness.
‏ما يؤدي إلى فقدانها الوعي،
However, it is not so.
‏لكن الواقع يخالف ذلك.
Estera, honey, you'll get cold.
‏"إستيرا"، يا عزيزتي، ستُصابين بالبرد.
Cover yourself.
‏غطّي نفسك.
Specialized blood vessel shunts prevent the blood from rapid draining.
‏تمنع تحويلات الأوعية الدموية المتخصصة ‏حدوث انقطاع سريع في الدماء الواصلة للدماغ.
They owe their survival to a life strategy developed over
‏إنها تدين ببقائها لإستراتيجية حياتية تطوّرت
millions of years.
‏على مدى ملايين السنين.
How graceful.
‏ما أرشقها!
Listen, you're not... the only one whose package is missing.
‏اسمع، لست الوحيد الذي فُقد طرده.
Mine is too. A gift for Maks.
‏لقد فُقد طردي أيضًا، وفيه هدية لـ"ماكس".
A hand-painted sailing ship model. Very hard to get.
‏نموذج لسفينة شراعية ملونة باليد، ‏يصعب الحصول على مثلها.
I'm sorry for the kid.
‏أشعر بالأسف على الولد.
Yeah, it cost me half my pay.
‏أجل، كلّفتني تلك الهدية نصف راتبي.
A kid should be loved, not bought with expensive gifts.
‏يحتاج الطفل إلى الحُب، ‏لا إلى هدايا باهظة الثمن.
Thanks, you've broadened my horizons.
‏شكرًا، وسّعت آفاقي بفضل حكمتك.
- You're compensating for something. - What do you care?
‏- أنت تعوضينه عن شيء ما. ‏- وما شأنك؟
You don't have to say if you don't want to. I already know.
‏إن شئت فلا تخبريني. أعرف سلفًا.
Know what?
‏ماذا تعرف؟
Well, I know... girls like you.
‏أعرف الفتيات مثلك.
Independent.
‏مستقلات،
Lonely, with emotional baggage.
‏وحيدات، يحملن تركة عاطفية ثقيلة.
Yeah? You got any other advice for me?
‏وماذا بعد؟ هل لديك نصيحة أخرى لي؟
You should try harder?
‏يجب أن تجتهدي أكثر؟
- I lost my tailpipe. - What?
‏- لقد انفكّ أنبوب عادم مركبتي. ‏- ماذا؟
My exhaust pipe is wobbling. Can you check it?
‏أنبوب العادم يتأرجح، هلّا تتفقد حاله؟
- Me? - In the back.
‏- أنا؟ ‏- إنه في الخلف.
God, what a clunker.
‏غير معقول، هذه السيارة خردة.
Moron.
‏أحمق!
New dress?
‏فستان جديد؟
Do you like it?
‏هل أعجبك؟
It's alright.
‏لا بأس به.
That's all?
‏أهذا كلّ شيء؟
The tailor said that... it was perfect.
‏قال الخيّاط إنه رائع.
- But I'm not sure. - You said he's a good tailor.
‏- لكني لست متأكدة. ‏- قلت إنه خيّاط ماهر.
You even wanted to buy him a gift or something.
‏حتى إنك أردت أن تشتري له هدية أو نحو ذلك.
I have.
‏لقد اشتريت.
He makes such beautiful things for others, but he himself is kind of...
‏إنه يصنع أشياء جميلة للآخرين، ‏لكن في المقابل،
transparent.
‏كأنّ لا أحد يراه.
Need help?
‏أتريدين مساعدة؟
Your hair.
‏ارفعي شعرك.
Thank you.
‏شكرًا.
Are we leaving already? It's still early.
‏هل سنغادر الآن؟ ما زال الوقت مبكرًا.
A seam ripped.
‏لقد انفتق الفستان.
Maybe the tailor's still open.
‏ربما لم يغلق الخيّاط بعد.
Is it still wobbling?
‏أما زال يتأرجح؟
You abandoned me here.
‏لقد تركتني هنا.
I spaced out. Are you getting in?
‏لقد شرد ذهني. هل ستركب؟
Your phone beeped or something.
‏لقد أصدر هاتفك تنبيهًا أو ما شابه.
Just don't get muck on the upholstery.
‏لا توسخ مفروشات السيارة.
Okay. Maybe let's go, 'cause...
‏حسنًا، هلّا ننطلق لأن…
- It's 4 p.m. - Maks. Uh, Maks comes first.
‏- الساعة 4 مساءً. ‏- الأولوية الكبرى لـ"ماكس".
- What? - I have to pick him up from the aunties.
‏- ماذا؟ ‏- عليّ إحضاره من عند العمّتين.
From w-where?
‏من أين؟
Our neighbors are taking care of my son.
‏جارتاي تعتنيان بابني،
They're going out for Christmas Eve. What don't you understand?
‏وستخرجان للاحتفال. ما الذي لا تفهمه؟
Okay.
‏مفهوم.
Mrs. Estera.
‏سيدة "إستيرا"…
I got your gift.
‏لقد استلمت هديتك.
It was surprising.
‏كانت مفاجأة.
We've known each other for so many years, so... maybe it's high time we...
‏يعرف كلّ منا الآخر منذ سنوات، ‏لذا ربما حان الوقت…
stopped being so official.
‏لرفع الكلفة بيننا.
Right.
‏صحيح.
A seam gave out.
‏لقد انفتق الدرز هنا.
I understood the message.
‏فهمت الرسالة.
You're a beautiful woman, Estera and...
‏أنت امرأة جميلة يا "إستيرا"،
if you're ready...
‏وإن كنت جاهزة،
then so am I.
‏فأنا جاهز كذلك.
I'm just here about the ripped seam.
‏لقد جئتُ من أجل إصلاح فتق الفستان فقط.
- Give me a minute. - Okay.
‏- أمهلني دقيقة. ‏- حسنًا.
- Honey... - Krzysiek, you were supposed to be home.
‏- عزيزتي… ‏- "كشيشك"، يُفترض أن تكون في البيت.
- Well... - Well?
‏- حسنًا… ‏- ماذا هناك؟
I, I, I know, Zuza, but let's not do this over the phone, okay?
‏أعرف يا "زوزيا"، ‏لكن لا أريد مناقشة الأمر على الهاتف.
Where exactly are you?
‏أين أنت بالضبط؟
- Yeah. Where am I? - Where?
‏- أجل، أين أنا؟ ‏- أين؟
- I'm lost. - Lost.
‏- أنا غارق. ‏- غارق.
I mean with my work.
‏أقصد أنا غارق في العمل.
- Everything's ready. You promised me. - Yeah.
‏- كلّ شيء جاهز. لقد وعدتني. ‏- أجل.
The parents are already here. You know this is important to me.
‏لقد جاء والداي، وأنت تعرف أهمية ذلك عندي.
When will you be back?
‏متى ستعود؟
In-in-in half an hour.
‏في غضون نصف ساعة.
Thank you very much. Have fun.
‏شكرًا جزيلًا. أتمنى لكما أوقاتًا ممتعة!
A visit with the family. Been waiting for this all year.
‏زيارة عائلية! ‏هذا ما كنت أترقبه طوال العام!
The cheesecake won't eat itself.
‏الـ"تشيز كيك" ينتظر من يأكله.
Come on. Bye.
‏هيّا بنا. وداعًا.
Mom...
‏أمي…
- Yes, honey? - I need to poop.
‏- نعم يا حبيبي؟ ‏- أريد أن أتغوط.
Fuck it.
‏تبًا!
Okay.
‏حسنًا.
It's an important day. And my first time on patrol.
‏إنه يوم مهم، وأول مرة لي في دورية.
Yeah.
‏أجل.
The city's empty, there's no one in the shops and thieves are having a field day.
‏المدينة فارغة، ولا أحد في المتاجر، ‏واللصوص يسرحون ويمرحون.
But there are no shops here.
‏لكن لا متاجر هنا.
There's nothing here.
‏لا يُوجد شيء هنا.
POLICE
‏"الشرطة"
Should I wipe the windshield? I will, eh?
‏هل أمسح الزجاج الأمامي؟ سأمسحه، اتفقنا؟
Its' a cool task.
‏إنها مهمة جميلة.
We used to have squad cars...
‏كانت سيارات دوريات الشرطة
that didn't even have ventilation.
‏غير مزودة بالتكييف.
Models from '95, '96... '98...
‏أتحدث عن سيارات من طراز عام 95، 96… 98…
That's the year I was born.
‏ذاك عام مولدي.
Hard to stay focused on a day like this, huh?
‏يصعب الحفاظ على التركيز في يوم كهذا، صحيح؟
Look!
‏انظر!
Officer Bogdan Kolenda, road check.
‏الضابط "بوغدان كوليندا"، تفتيش مروريّ.
- Papers, please. - Sure.
‏- الأوراق من فضلك. ‏- بكل سرور.
Excuse me, could we get this done rather quickly? I can pay the ticket.
‏عفوًا، هل يمكننا إتمام الإجراءات بسرعة؟ ‏يمكنني دفع الغرامة.
- Who is the vehicle's owner? - I am.
‏- من مالك هذه المركبة؟ ‏- أنا.
- Maria Kwiecień? - No. I mean yes!
‏- "ماريا كفيتشن"؟ ‏- لا، بل أقصد نعم.
Jan Maria Kwiecień. That's my name.
‏"يان ماريا كفيتشن"، هذا اسمي.
But it was too long to fit in the registration papers.
‏لكن لم تتسع له أوراق التسجيل ‏لأنه طويل جدًا.
Okay, so...
‏حسنًا، إذًا…
How much?
‏كم الغرامة؟
- He's trying to make an illegal payment... - N-no, n-n-not illegal...
‏- إنه يحاول دفع رشوة… ‏- لا، ليست رشوة…
Sir, this vehicle's technical inspection is overdue.
‏سيدي، شهادة الفحص الفني ‏لهذه المركبة منتهية الصلاحية.
Of course it is.
‏بالطبع، هي كذلك.
'Cause formally...
‏من الناحية الرسمية،
this isn't my car.
‏هذه ليست مركبتي.
- Oh! - Then whose is it?
‏ولمن هي؟
My friend's.
‏لصديقتي.
I mean a distant friend... actually, really, she's a complete stranger to me, yeah?
‏أقصد أنها صديقة غير مقرّبة، ‏بل إنها غريبة لا أعرفها مطلقًا، أتفهمان؟
How much?
‏كم الغرامة؟
Sir, this car will be impounded.
‏سيدي، سيتم حجز هذه السيارة.
Please wait here while we contact the HQ.
‏من فضلك، انتظر هنا ‏بينما نتصل بمقر القيادة.
"How much?"
‏"كم الغرامة؟"
POLICE
‏"الشرطة"
Hello? Hello?
‏هل تسمعني؟
- I think it's broken. - You gotta press the button.
‏- أعتقد أنه معطل. ‏- عليك الضغط على الزر.
Here 314, come in, 200.
‏هنا 314، حوّل يا 200.
The car's definitely stolen. We have to arrest him.
‏تلك المركبة مسروقة حتمًا. علينا أن نعتقله.
- He's playing hard to get! - Jesus.
‏- إنه يقاوم ويتحدى الأوامر. ‏- يا للهول!
- I think I see him. - Yeah, yeah.
‏- أظن أنه في مجال رؤيتي. ‏- أجل.
- I can't see him. - Go right!
‏- لا أراه. ‏- فلتنعطف إلى اليمين.
- Or maybe left? - No, no, right, right.
‏- أو ربما إلى اليسار؟ ‏- لا، بل اليمين.
- Here? - What?
‏- هنا؟ ‏- ماذا؟
- Here. - That? That's a trash container.
‏- هنا. ‏- تلك؟ إنها حاوية قمامة.
Really?
‏حقًا؟
You blocked someone, so I had to move the car. He kept honking his horn.
‏عرقلت مركبتك أحدهم، ‏فحرّكتُها لأنه لم يكفّ عن التزمير.
- What is this? - What?
‏- ما هذا؟ ‏- ماذا تقصدين؟
It was like that this morning.
‏هكذا كانت منذ الصباح.
- It was loose. - Maksiu, get in, okay? It's warm inside.
‏- كانت متخلخلة. ‏- اركب يا "ماكشو". الجو دافئ في الداخل.
You wrecked my car!
‏لقد حطّمت سيارتي.
Okay, Marysia, I'll call a cab. There's no time.
‏حسنًا يا "ماريشا"، سأتصل بسيارة أجرة. ‏ليس هناك وقت.
You're not getting into this car again. Goodbye.
‏لن تركب هذه المركبة مرة أخرى. مع السلامة.
Oh, come on!
‏بالله عليك!
Leave it!
‏لا تلمسها!
This is the worst day of my life.
‏هذا أسوأ يوم في حياتي.
I take the subway to work. I, I, I can't park!
‏أذهب إلى عملي بمترو الأنفاق، ‏لأني لا أجيد صفّ السيارات.
And I was rude and...
‏لقد كنت فظًا معك و…
We started off on the wrong foot, Marysia.
‏بدأ تعارفنا بداية كارثية يا "ماريشا".
I'm sorry.
‏أنا آسف.
Is he coming with us?
‏هل سيأتي معنا؟
I don't really know.
‏لا أعرف.
I wanted to... propose today, but nothing is going as it should.
‏أردت أن أخطب حبيبتي اليوم، ‏لكن لا شيء يسير كما ينبغي.
Well, I have to agree with that.
‏أتفق معك في ذلك.
Before she died, Grandma promised me that if I wanted to get married,
‏قبل وفاتها، ‏وعدتني جدتي أنني إذا أردت الزواج،
Grandpa would give it to me for luck and...
‏فسيعطيني جدّي إياه لجلب الحظ السعيد و…
I really need that luck.
‏أنا بحاجة ماسة إلى هذا الحظ السعيد.
Get in.
‏اركب.
Don't make me regret this.
‏لا تجعلني أندم على هذا.
Mom, will there be a gift when we get back?
‏أمي، هل سأحصل على هدية لدى عودتنا؟
Yes, honey.
‏نعم يا عزيزي.
Because I'm kinda hungry. Could I have the "emergency" gummies?
‏أنا جائع قليلًا، ‏فهل يمكنني تناول سكاكر "الطوارئ"؟
Sorry, Maks, but... I ate them.
‏آسفة يا "ماكس"، لقد أكلتُها.
I have a candy bar.
‏معي قطعة حلوى.
I don't like raisins.
‏لا أحب الزبيب.
Then I'll... Cool, I'll eat the raisins.
‏لا بأس، أنا سآكل الزبيب.
- Okay? - Mhm.
‏اتفقنا؟
- Stop! - What?
‏- توقّفي. ‏- ماذا؟
- Stop the car! Turn off the lights.
‏- أوقفي السيارة وأطفئي المصابيح.
Kill the engine.
‏أطفئي المحرك.
- What? What's going on? - Marysia, there's a squad car there.
‏- ما القصة؟ ‏- "ماريشا"، هناك سيارة شرطة.
So what?
‏وإن يكن؟
Do you know your technical inspection is overdue?
‏ألم تفوّتي موعد الفحص الفني؟
How do you know that?
‏وكيف عرفت ذلك؟
I checked, uh, your glove compartment out of boredom.
‏نظرت في صندوق التابلوه من الملل.
Maks, get down.
‏انبطح يا "ماكس".
I'm really sorry, son.
‏أنا آسفة يا ولدي.
I'll get a chance to... revise our plans, okay?
‏سأحرص على مراجعة خططنا، اتفقنا؟
Mom, this is better than normal Christmas!
‏أمي، هذا أجمل من عيد الميلاد العادي!
POLICE
‏"الشرطة"
They are leaving.
‏سيذهبان.
You're sticking out. Lay down.
‏رأسك ظاهر. انبطح.
- What? - Lay down.
‏- ماذا؟ ‏- انبطح.
What are you doing there? They've gone already.
‏ماذا تفعلان عندكما؟ لقد رحلا.
Today in Bethlehem There is good news
‏"اليوم في (بيت لحم) جاءت البشرى
Michał?
‏"ميخاو"؟
What are you doing there?
‏ماذا تفعل عندك؟
The carburetor?
‏أفحص المكربن؟
'Cause sometimes I think... that you come here to hide from me.
‏يُخيّل إليّ أحيانًا ‏أنك تأتي إلى هنا لتختبئ منّي.
No.
‏لا.
I was actually happy that there's going to be a baby.
‏كنت سعيدة بقدوم الطفل.
But maybe it's better this way.
‏لكن ربما هذا أفضل.
The boy has to mature. It will happen by itself.
‏يجب أن ينضج ولدُنا. سيحدث ذلك تلقائيًا.
The only thing that happens by itself is rusting.
‏لا شيء يحدث تلقائيًا سوى الصدأ.
- It's for your own good, Mirek. - I know you'll manage.
‏- هذا لمصلحتك يا "ميريك". ‏- أعلم أنك ستتدبر أمرك.
But today?
‏لكن اليوم؟
There's never a good time.
‏ليس هناك وقت مناسب.
Maksiu... just this and one more place and we're done, okay?
‏"ماكشو"، بقي هذا العنوان ‏وعنوان آخر حتى ننتهي، اتفقنا؟
- Should I go with you? - If you want to.
‏- هل آتي معك؟ ‏- كما تشاء.
Okay.
‏حسنًا.
Well... it's Christmas Eve.
‏إنها عشية عيد الميلاد.
Hold up. This is where your or mine parcel is.
‏انتظر. في هذا المكان سنجد طردك أو طردي.
There's a light on!
‏أرى مصباحًا مضاء.
Um, give me a leg up.
‏ارفعني.
- How? - Normally, just crouch down.
‏- كيف؟ ‏- اركع بشكل طبيعي.
Okay. Let's do this.
‏حسنًا. فلنفعل ذلك.
- Just stop wiggling around. - Then get up. Get up now.
‏- كفّي عن الهز. ‏- انهض الآن.
- This isn't actually funny! - Turn around! But I'm ticklish... wrong way!
‏- هذا ليس مضحكًا. ‏- استدر. أشعر بالدغدغة… استدرت بالعكس.
Where are you ticklish?
‏أين تشعرين بالدغدغة؟
- On... on my thighs! - What?
‏- من فخذيّ. ‏- ماذا؟
- Who has ticklish thighs? - Well, I do!
‏- من يشعر بالدغدغة من فخذيه؟ ‏- أنا.
I am!
‏أنا.
- Oh, hello. - Merry Christmas.
‏- مرحبًا. ‏- ميلادًا مجيدًا!
This is the proper package.
‏هذا هو الطرد الصحيح.
And... this package opened the heart of a wonderful woman to me.
‏لقد فتح هذا الطرد لي قلب امرأة رائعة.
Have you been... together long?
‏هل أنتما مرتبطان منذ مدة طويلة؟
Us? No.
‏نحن؟ لا.
- No... - No, it's a misunderstanding.
‏- لا… ‏- لا، هذا سوء تفاهم.
Sometimes misunderstandings are the start of wonderful things.
‏أحيانًا يكون سوء التفاهم ‏بداية لأشياء رائعة.
I should go.
‏عليّ الذهاب.
Just a bit more... and Zuza will be all yours.
‏قليلًا بعد، وستصبح "زوزا" امرأتك وحدك.
- Wasn't this supposed to be a ship? - It will be once I find it.
‏- ألا يُفترض أن يحتوي الطرد سفينة؟ ‏- هو كذلك في طرد العنوان التالي.
- And what is this? - Mm... your lucky charm.
‏- وما هذا؟ ‏- تميمة حظك.
- What charm? - For luck.
‏- أيّ تميمة؟ ‏- لجلب الحظ السعيد.
This was supposed to be Grandma's ring for Zuza.
‏كان يُفترض أن أستلم ‏خاتم جدتي حتى أقدّمه لـ"زوزا".
So, we've... we've misunderstood each other...
‏وقع بيننا سوء تفاهم…
But what... what's there to misunderstand?
‏لكن ما الذي يمكن أن يُساء فهمه هنا؟
I don't know. Maybe Grandpa thought that... this would do you more good.
‏لا أعلم. ربما ظن جدّك ‏أن هذا التمثال سينفعك أكثر.
- Sorry, it's a dumb joke, I know... - No, no, no. This has to be a mistake.
‏- أنا آسفة، أعلم أنها مزحة سمجة… ‏- غير ممكن، لا بد أن هذا خطأ.
There have to be other packages somewhere that were...
‏لا بد أن هناك طرودًا في مكان آخر…
I don't know, misplaced.
‏ربما سُلمت بالخطأ.
I was with Grandpa when he wrapped this.
‏كنت مع جدّك حين غلّف هذا التمثال.
And you couldn't tell me that all this time I've been chasing a prick?
‏ألم تستطيعي إخباري قبلًا ‏أني كنت أقتفي أثر قضيب؟
How was I to know you were expecting a ring?
‏وكيف لي أن أعرف أنك تتوقع خاتمًا؟
Have you ever seen someone propose with a cock?
‏هل سبق أن رأيت رجلًا ‏يخطب امرأة بتقديم قضيب لها؟
I'm sorry. It seemed really plausible to me...
‏أنا آسفة. بدا الأمر لي معقولًا…
No...
‏لا…
This Christmas was supposed to be special.
‏كان يُفترض أن يكون هذا العيد مميزًا.
And it is.
‏وهو كذلك.
- Santa, Santa! - Hello?
‏- "بابا نويل"! ‏- مرحبًا؟
See? It's not Santa.
‏أرأيت؟ ليس "بابا نويل".
Just some chick and a dude. Maybe they're selling wafers.
‏إنهما مجرّد شابة وشابّ، ‏وربما يبيعان خُبز المناولة.
Uh, hi. Is there an adult in the house?
‏مرحبًا. هل يُوجد شخص كبير في البيت؟
Mom's flight was cancelled.
‏لقد أُلغيت رحلة أمي.
Dad went somewhere on a repair.
‏وذهب أبي إلى مكان ما في مهمة إصلاح.
I'm the oldest.
‏أنا الأكبر سنًا هنا.
I'm from the courier company. There was a package on your doorstep this morning.
‏أنا من شركة البريد السريع. ‏كان هناك طرد على عتبة بيتكم هذا الصباح.
Come in. I'll call Dad.
‏ادخلا. سأتصل بأبي.
Okay.
‏حسنًا.
What should I say?
‏ماذا أقول له؟
Nothing.
‏لا شيء.
You're in luck. The gift ended up...
‏أنتم محظوظون. صارت الهدية
in the right hands. But this package is for you as well.
‏مع الشخص المناسب. لكن هذا الطرد لكم أيضًا.
It's from mommy!
‏إنه من أمي.
Oh, no. Dammit. Not now, baby.
‏لا، تبًا! ليس الآن يا سيارتي الحلوة.
- Gas? - Diesel.
‏- البنزين؟ ‏- المازوت.
Is there, uh, a station nearby?
‏هل هناك محطة وقود قريبة؟
That way, but it's quite far from here.
‏من ذاك الطريق، لكنها بعيدة.
Okay...
‏حسنًا…
Hello?
‏نعم؟
- Kama? - Hi.
‏- "كاما"؟ ‏- مرحبًا.
I'm sorry for bothering you tonight, darling, but there's a problem.
‏أنا آسفة لإزعاجك الليلة يا عزيزتي، ‏لكن هناك مشكلة.
Could you send me someone with a canister?
‏هلّا ترسلين إليّ صفيحة وقود؟
- I... - Hello?
‏- أنا… ‏- هل تسمعينني؟
I can't believe it.
‏غير معقول!
Oh. Then maybe I'll use my phone and call a taxi.
‏إذًا ربما عليّ طلب سيارة أجرة من هاتفي.
No, it's... there's music playing.
‏لم يردّ… أسمع أنغامًا موسيقية.
Fine, screw it.
‏حسنًا، تبًا لهذا!
Meaning?
‏ماذا تقصدين؟
I live there.
‏بيتي هناك.
I screwed up Maks' Christmas Eve. I'll at least get him to bed.
‏أفسدتُ ليلة العيد على "ماكس". ‏سأضعه في السرير على الأقل.
Can you lock up the car? Just press the beeper, yeah?
‏هلّا تُقفل السيارة؟ اضغط الزر فقط.
I'll carry Maks.
‏أنا سأحمل "ماكس".
Could you take this toy out of my pocket?
‏هلّا تُخرجين هذه اللعبة من جيبي؟
Why? Does it hurt you?
‏لماذا؟ هل تؤلمك؟
Okay.
‏حسنًا.
- Lay down him there. - His jacket.
‏- ضعه هناك. ‏- ومعطفه؟
Later.
‏سأنزعه لاحقًا.
And what about his gift?
‏وماذا عن هديته؟
I don't know. I'll give him some knick-knack. I have some stashed away.
‏لا أعلم. سأعطيه لعبة صغيرة. ‏لديّ بعض الألعاب المخبأة.
I'll tell him the ship didn't get here, because...
‏سأقول له إنّ السفينة لم تصل
the reindeer got a hernia, and Santa got delayed.
‏لأن "بابا نويل" تأخر ‏بسبب إصابة الرنة بفتق.
We don't always get what we want, huh?
‏ما كلّ ما يتمنى المرء يدركه، صحيح؟
Wait a moment.
‏انتظر لحظة.
You know what? 'Cause...
‏أتعلمين أمرًا؟ بما أنك…
you, you're... you're probably tired too and... and I...
‏لا بد أنك متعبة، وأنا…
FOR FOREVER
‏"إلى الأبد"
my feet have been wet for an hour, so...
‏…قدماي مبللتان منذ ساعة لذا…
Give it to Zuza.
‏قدّمه إلى "زوزيا".
No...
‏لا…
Give it to your Zuza.
‏قدّمه إلى حبيبتك "زوزيا".
No, no, I'm sorry. I can't take it.
‏لا، أنا آسف، لا يمكنني أخذه.
Well... It might not be from Grandma, but... it's quite nice.
‏قد لا يكون من جدتك، لكنه جميل جدًا.
It's only catching dust here and I... don't see any prospects for it.
‏الغبار يتراكم عليه هنا، ‏ولا أرى أيّ آفاق مستقبلية له.
You'll propose... and it'll be great.
‏سوف تخطب حبيبتك، وسيكون ذلك رائعًا.
Your friends will visit you and say: "Wow... what a perfect couple".
‏سيزوركما أصدقاؤكما ويقولون، ‏"يا لكما من زوجين رائعين!"
So sweet... it makes you sick.
‏سيدور رأسك من فرط الحلاوة.
Go. You have something to do.
‏اذهب، لديك مهمة تنتظرك.
Thank you.
‏شكرًا لك.
25TH DECEMBER
‏"25 ديسمبر"
- Hi. - Hi, kid. May I?
‏- مرحبًا. ‏- مرحبًا يا فتى. هل يمكنني الدخول؟
Is your mom in?
‏هل أمك في البيت؟
No.
‏لا.
Okay.
‏حسنًا.
SEVERAL HOURS EARLIER
‏"قبل عدة ساعات"
Who did you land yourself there?
‏مع من ورطت نفسك؟
We saw him leave.
‏رأيناه يغادر.
You didn't brag about him. He's a cutie...
‏لم تتفاخري به. إنه وسيم.
Meh. His hair looked weird...
‏لا أتفق معك. شكلُ شعره غريب…
No, it... That was nobody.
‏ليس… ليس شخصًا مهمًا.
So, you don't have any... plans for the rest of the evening?
‏إذًا أليست لديك خطط لبقية السهرة؟
And we... also have cake.
‏ولدينا كعكة أيضًا.
- Come over. Come! - Go.
‏- تعاليا إلى بيتي. ‏- هيّا.
So, I tell him that it doesn't matter what it's called.
‏وقلت له لا يهم ما اسم هذه العلاقة.
I don't know myself.
‏أنا نفسي لا أعرف.
But since we... started living together,
‏لكن منذ أن انتقلنا للعيش تحت سقف واحد،
it's been the most beautiful time of my life.
‏وأنا أعيش أحلى أيام حياتي.
Here's to you!
‏بصحتكما!
Are we expecting anyone?
‏هل نتوقع قدوم أحد؟
Kama? Come in! Come inside.
‏"كاما"؟ تعالي، ادخلي.
- You're alive. - I am.
‏- أنت حية. ‏- أجل.
- Yeah. - Kamila.
‏- هذه "كاميلا".
What happened to your phone?
‏ماذا حدث لهاتفك؟
- I was worried sick, girl! - Sorry! I completely forgot.
‏- لقد قلقت جدًا يا فتاة. ‏- آسفة. لقد نسيت تمامًا.
A gift.
‏هدية لك.
- What's that? - Diesel.
‏- ما هذا؟ ‏- مازوت.
This year, I'm doing it. I checked.
‏سأفعلها هذا العام. لقد تحققت من الأمر.
A plane to Malawi, then along the Zambezi... all the way to Botswana.
‏سأسافر جوًا إلى "مالاوي"، ‏ثم سأبحر في نهر "زامبيزي" إلى "بوتسوانا".
- Oh! Botswana? - The wildest place on Earth.
‏- "بوتسوانا"؟ ‏- المنطقة الأغنى بالحياة البرية في العالم.
- That's my main New Year's resolution. - Good luck!
‏- هذا قراري الرئيسي في العام الجديد. ‏- حالفك التوفيق!
Your husband keeps saying the same thing ever year and nothing!
‏يكرر زوجك الأسطوانة نفسها كلّ عام ‏ولا يفعل شيئًا.
What about New Year's Eve? You got any plans?
‏ماذا عن ليلة رأس السنة؟ هل لديك أيّ خطط؟
Sex all night long.
‏ممارسة الجنس طوال الليل.
What are we doing, Ester? I don't recall.
‏ماذا سنفعل يا "إستير"؟ لا أذكر.
Is it that tailor?
‏مع ذلك الخياط؟
I want to feel that I'm still alive, Eryk.
‏أريد أن أشعر أنني ما زلت حية يا "إريك".
So, what now?
‏وما العمل الآن؟
Our whole life down the drain.
‏ذهبت كلّ حياتنا هباء.
You always wanted to travel.
‏لطالما أردت أن تسافر.
But you didn't.
‏لكنك لم ترغبي في ذلك.
Go.
‏اذهب.
Go to those giraffes, antelopes, meerkats...
‏اذهب إلى تلك الزرافات والظباء والنموس…
- You think? - I love you and I want you to be happy.
‏- أهذا رأيك؟ ‏- أنا أحبّك وأريد أن تكون سعيدًا.
What about you?
‏وماذا عنك؟
I'll order another dress.
‏سأطلب تفصيل فستان آخر.
Oh, there you are!
‏أنت هنا!
'Cause I got off here and then went there. But you weren't there and...
‏نزلت من الحافلة هنا، ‏ثم ذهبت إلى هناك، لكن لم أجدك…
- My folks' place is there. - Okay.
‏- بيت أهلي هناك. ‏- فهمت.
You invited me to your folks' place?
‏هل دعوتني إلى بيت أهلك؟
Well, I live...
‏في الواقع، أنا أعيش…
I mean... I lived with my parents.
‏أقصد أني كنت أعيش مع والديّ.
Milena, what exactly did you send me, eh?
‏"ميلينا"، ماذا أرسلت إليّ بالضبط؟
So... you haven't seen it yet?
‏ألم تشاهده بعد؟
Dude, you made a bet with me and I won.
‏يا صاح، لقد تراهنّا وأنا فزت.
Now it's your turn to do a task.
‏والآن حان دورك للقيام بمهمة.
Marysia!
‏"ماريشا"!
Hey. Hey. Hey.
‏اسمع.
- What are you doing here? - I'm loo-looking for you.
‏- ماذا تفعل هنا؟ ‏- إني أبحث عنك.
Shouldn't you be home?
‏ألا ينبغي أن تكون في بيتك؟
I don't have a home.
‏ليس لديّ بيت.
I live with my parents.
‏أنا أعيش مع والديّ.
I don't have anyone.
‏أنا وحيد.
- Easy. Come on, let's sit. Over there. - Come on, come over there. Easy.
‏- على مهلك. فلنجلس هناك. ‏- هيّا، فلنجلس هناك. على مهلك.
I've lived with them...
‏أعيش معهما
- for 38 years. - Right.
‏- منذ 38 عامًا. ‏- حسنًا.
Uh, let's sit and talk.
‏فلنجلس ونتحدث.
That's just life. Come on.
‏هذه هي الحياة. هيّا.
- Marysia... - Sit down.
‏- "ماريشا"… ‏- اجلس.
- Yeah?
‏- نعم؟
- I need to tell you something. - What?
‏- يجب أن أخبرك بشيء. ‏- ما هو؟
- Shoot. - I changed around those packages.
‏- هات ما لديك. ‏- أنا من تلاعب بالطرود.
Why did you do that?
‏ولم فعلت ذلك؟
'Cause I...
‏لأنني…
'Cause I'm a lion.
‏لأنني أسد.
What you and I had was...
‏ما كان بيننا…
it was fire.
‏كانت جذوة حُب.
- What are you saying? - When you left me...
‏- عمّ تتحدث؟ ‏- حين تركتني…
I know you think I could have tons of women like that.
‏أعلم أنك تعتقدين ‏أن بوسعي أن أحظى بملايين النساء.
But I don't.
‏لكني لست كذلك.
I'm sorry.
‏أنا آسف.
You know what it means to be... alone in the world.
‏تعرفين ما معنى ‏أن يكون المرء وحيدًا في هذا العالم.
Uh, I met Santa in the parking lot.
‏قابلتُ "بابا نويل" في موقف السيارات.
He asked about you and said that... the reindeer, uh, has...
‏سأل عنك وقال إنّ الرنة أُصيبت
a hernia. Mom told you, right?
‏بفتق. أخبرتك أمك بالأمر، صحيح؟
She said he had a bad hoof.
‏قالت إنّ حافره مُصاب.
Yeah. Yeah. A bad hoof.
‏أجل، حافره مُصاب.
So... he didn't have time to wrap this.
‏على أيّ حال، لم يكن لديه وقت لتغليف هذه.
Here.
‏تفضّل.
No "Merry Christmas"?
‏ألن تقول لي "ميلادًا مجيدًا"؟
I didn't propose.
‏لم أخطب.
We split up.
‏لقد انفصلنا.
Well... good riddance to bad boats.
‏حمدًا للرب على الخلاص والسلامة، قدّر ولطف!
Just... a bit of compassion?
‏هلّا أظهرت قليلًا من التعاطف؟
For once.
‏ولو مرة.
Oh... As they say: The morning's rain and a girl's pain.
‏كما يُقال، "أمطار الصباح ودموع الفتيات،
Both don't last long.
‏كلاهما لا يدوم طويلًا."
You had a pretty good childhood, right?
‏حظيت بطفولة جميلة، صحيح؟
What?
‏ماذا؟
What other kid had a monkey at home?
‏هل تعرف طفلًا آخر كان في بيته قرد؟
Some had a monkey at home,
‏كان لدى البعض قرد في بيتهم،
others – a normal grandfather, huh?
‏وكان لدى البعض الآخر جدّ طبيعي.
You know that...
‏كما تعرف،
you can always stay here.
‏يمكنك دائمًا الإقامة هنا.
That's still your room.
‏ما زالت غرفتك هناك.
Thanks.
‏شكرًا.
Where did all this come from?
‏من أين جاءت كلّ هذه الأشياء؟
Krzysiek brought it.
‏"كشيشك" أحضرها.
Yesterday, I lied to you and the captain.
‏بالأمس، غافلتُك أنت والقبطان.
What's wrong, honey?
‏ما الخطب يا عزيزي؟
I wanted a ship like this too, so I took the smallest one.
‏أردتُ اقتناء سفينة كهذه أيضًا، ‏لذا أخذت أصغر سفينة.
I didn't know I'd get more today.
‏لم أكن أعلم أني سأحصل على غيرها اليوم.
- You snatched it, mm? - Yes.
‏- هل سرقتها؟ ‏- نعم.
Come on. We'll escort Zbigniew home.
‏هيّا. سنأخذ "زبيغنيف" إلى بيته.
You'll explain everything to me on the way and we'll return the ship, hm?
‏ستشرح لي كلّ شيء في الطريق، ‏وسنعيد السفينة، اتفقنا؟
- Good afternoon.
‏- طاب يومك.
We're here on, uh, a special task,
‏لقد جئنا في مهمة خاصة.
What a beautiful schooner!
‏ما أجمل هذه السفينة الشراعية!
I'm sorry. I... snatched it.
‏أنا آسف. لقد سرقتها.
Oh, it's mine!
‏إنها لي!
Don't worry about it. I once stole too – a compass.
‏لا تقلق. أنا أيضًا سرقت بوصلة ذات مرة.
But he shouldn't have done that, right? Maks is very sorry.
‏لكن ما كان ينبغي أن يفعل ذلك، صحيح؟ ‏"ماكس" نادم جدًا.
Nonsense! A man has to get through life somehow.
‏كلام فارغ! ‏على المرء تدبير أموره في الحياة بطريقة ما.
Here! As a gift from me, you sea dog.
‏تفضّل! خذها هدية منّي أيها الملّاح العظيم.
I've got tons of such junk.
‏لديّ الكثير من هذه الخردة.
Come in, I'll show you.
‏ادخل، سأريك إياها.
Tea?
‏أتريدان شايًا؟
Only for a moment.
‏سنبقى قليلًا فقط.
You're probably busy with Christmas and...
‏ربما تكون مشغولًا بالعيد و…
What are you talking about?
‏عمّ تتحدثين؟
My grandson is moving in with me to guide me in my old age.
‏سينتقل حفيدي للعيش معي ‏حتى يرشدني في شيخوختي.
Krzysiek?
‏"كشيشك"؟
But... since when?
‏لكن منذ متى؟
Well... he's moving out of his girlfriend's.
‏سينتقل من بيت صديقته.
He just went to get his stuff.
‏لقد ذهب لتوه لإحضار أغراضه.
Maybe a piece of this... cheese.
‏ربما سأتناول قطعة من هذا الجبن.
You'll quickly get promoted.
‏ستنالين ترقية بسرعة.
Yeah.
‏أجل.
That's my wish for you.
‏هذا ما أتمناه لك،
For Christmas and... your whole life.
‏في عيد الميلاد ومدى الحياة.
- That's him! Bogdan, that's him! - Okay, let's go.
‏- هذا هو! يا "بوغدان"، هذا هو! ‏- حسنًا، فلننطلق.
- Slowly, but surely. - Mhm.
‏- ببطء، لكن بثبات. ‏- فهمت.
Come on, switch on! I got the controller wet.
‏هيّا، اشتغلي! ‏لقد بللتُ وحدة التحكم بمكبر الصوت.
- Hello? - Hello, hi. I'm calling, 'cause...
‏- نعم؟ ‏- مرحبًا. اتصلتُ لأن…
Right! Thanks for standing in for the reindeer.
‏نعم! شكرًا لأنك حللت محلّ الرنة.
No. I'm really sorry, Marysia, but there's a squad car after you.
‏لا، أنا آسف يا "ماريشا"، ‏لكن هناك سيارة شرطة تلاحقك.
What is it with you and squad cars, huh?
‏ما قصتك مع سيارات الشرطة؟
I haven't told you everything. You're in serious trouble.
‏لم أخبرك بكل شيء. أنت في ورطة كبيرة.
Why am I in trouble?
‏ولم أنا في ورطة؟
I-I'll explain everything in a sec...
‏سأشرح كلّ شيء بعد لحظة…
- Dammit! - Hello?
‏- اللعنة! ‏- هل تسمعني؟
He-hello?
‏هل تسمعينني؟
Fuck it.
‏تبًا!
POLICE
‏"الشرطة"
Jan Maria Kwiecień.
‏"يان ماريا كفيتشن".
Mom!
‏أمي!
Officer Barbara Pasterz. Please step out of the vehicle.
‏الضابطة "باربرا باستش". ‏من فضلك، اخرجي من السيارة.
So, Jan Maria Kwiecień testifies that he did this for you...
‏يشهد "يان ماريا كفيتشن" ‏أنه فعل ذلك من أجلك…
Maria Kwiecień!
‏"ماريا كفيتشن"!
This lady i-i-is... is unfortunately right.
‏هذه السيدة محقة للأسف.
And maybe I wanted to help in the beginning,
‏ربما أردت المساعدة في البداية
- but... - Mom...
‏- لكن… ‏- يا أمي…
Zbyszek is barely moving anymore.
‏لم يعُد "زبيشك" يتحرك إلا بشق الأنفس.
Why doesn't that fish have any water?
‏لم هذه السمكة بلا ماء؟
It splashed out. We were just on our way to the river.
‏لقد تناثر الماء. كنا في طريقنا إلى النهر.
Listen, he won't make it much longer.
‏اسمعا، لن تصمد هذه السمكة أكثر.
- Release the animal and return. - Ouch.
‏- أطلقا سراح السمكة وارجعا. ‏- أخ!
And behave.
‏وتأدّبا.
You're being watched.
‏أنتما تحت المراقبة.
Maks, you coming?
‏هل ستأتي يا "ماكس"؟
No, I'm staying here.
‏لا، سأبقى هنا.
- What are you doing? - So he gets used to the temperature.
‏- لم تفعل ذلك؟ ‏- حتى يعتاد على درجة الحرارة.
It's a carp. He just adapts to new conditions.
‏إنه شبوط، ‏يتكيف مع الظروف الجديدة بكل بساطة.
Yeah? Just like you.
‏حقًا؟ مثلك تمامًا.
I've got something for you.
‏لديّ شيء لك.
I'll release him.
‏سأطلق سراحه.
It's not swimming away. It's turning around?
‏إنه لا يسبح بعيدًا. هل سيستدير؟
Zbyszek, wetness all around. Reach out. Be happy.
‏"زبيشك"، الرطوبة في كلّ حدب وصوب. ‏الزعانف جانبًا رفع. نحو الفرح.
The new life awaits you.
‏الحياة الجديدة تنتظرك.
Go for it.
‏هيّا، انطلق!
Ouch.
‏أخ!
Damn. My fingers got... fat.
‏تبًا! لقد ثخنت أصابعي.
You threw the ring away?!
‏هل رميت الخاتم؟
No. It slipped.
‏لا، بل انزلق من يدي.
Why did you do that?
‏لم فعلت ذلك؟
That was my emotional baggage.
‏كان ذلك تركتي العاطفية الثقيلة.
Yours too, kinda.
‏وتركتك أيضًا إلى حد ما.
We've got a carte blanche before us.
‏نحن أمام صفحة جديدة.
Carp blanche.
‏سمكة جديدة.
- It's unpacked yet. - Hi, Daddy!
‏- لم نفتح الطرد بعد. ‏- "مرحبًا يا أبي!"
Look, we have a Christmas tree!
‏انظري، لدينا شجرة عيد الميلاد.
It comes together...
‏إنها تنسجم…
- Put Daddy on. - Daddy, it's Mom.
‏- أعطي والدك الهاتف. ‏- أبي، هذه أمي.
Give me this.
‏أعطيني هذا.
Aren't we too old for this?
‏ألم نكبر على ذلك؟
This is the most beautiful gift ever!
‏هذه أجمل هدية في العالم!
I think we've gone crazy in our old age.
‏أعتقد أننا فقدنا رشدنا في شيخوختنا.
See? There will be a wedding!
‏أرأيت؟ سيُقام عُرس.
Delicious!
‏لذيذ.
'Cause I've got experience.
‏لأني صاحب خبرة.
Subtitle by: Hellen Wanjiku
‏ترجمة "ديمة قشقارة"